<Infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false">

<!-- Addon for NT: Lobotomy -->

<ntg.section.lobopositiveeffects>Positive Lobotomy Effects</ntg.section.lobopositiveeffects>
<ntg.section.lobonegativeeffects>Neutral / Negative Lobotomy Effects</ntg.section.lobonegativeeffects>

<!-- Orbitoclast -->
<ntg.title.orbitoclast>Orbitoclast</ntg.title.orbitoclast>
<ntg.description.orbitoclast>Medical Skill Check: 60.
\nA surgical instrument used for performing transorbital lobotomies. It is inserted through the eye socket to be 'expertly' spun around and turn part of the brain into mush.
\nUsed for the quick and easy method of lobotomizing, though its results leave much to be desired.
\nIt can be removed from the head by using Skin Retractors.
</ntg.description.orbitoclast>
<ntg.applicationsuccess.orbitoclast>
    Readies the Orbitoclast in the eye socket to be hit with a hammer
</ntg.applicationsuccess.orbitoclast>
<ntg.applicationfailed.orbitoclast>
    Readies the Orbitoclast in the eye socket to be hit with a hammer |
    [bleeding] Bleeding (Between 1 and 20 strength) |
    Eye damage (Between 1 and 20 strength) |
    Extreme pain
</ntg.applicationfailed.orbitoclast>
<ntg.seealso.orbitoclast>
    [surgical_hammer] Surgical Hammer |
    [transorbital_lobotomy] Transorbital Lobotomy
</ntg.seealso.orbitoclast>

<!-- Surgical Hammer -->
<ntg.title.surgical_hammer>Surgical Hammer</ntg.title.surgical_hammer>
<ntg.description.surgical_hammer>Medical Skill Check: 60.
\nA fancy hammer used for pushing the orbitoclast through the eye socket, allowing it to be 'expertly' spun around and turn part of the brain into mush.
\nUsed for the quick and easy method of lobotomizing, though its results leave much to be desired. Requires the Orbitoclast to be placed before using.
</ntg.description.surgical_hammer>
<ntg.applicationsuccess.surgical_hammer>
    Slams the Orbitoclast into the brain, performing a succesful lobotomy
</ntg.applicationsuccess.surgical_hammer>
<ntg.applicationfailed.surgical_hammer>
    Slams the Orbitoclast into the brain, performing a failed lobotomy |
    [bleeding] Bleeding (Between 1 and 10 strength) |
    Eye damage (Between 1 and 20 strength) |
    Extreme pain |
</ntg.applicationfailed.surgical_hammer>
<ntg.seealso.surgical_hammer>
    [orbitoclast] Orbitoclast |
    [transorbital_lobotomy] Transorbital Lobotomy
</ntg.seealso.surgical_hammer>

<!-- Nerve Generators / CRC -->
<ntg.title.nerve_generators>Cerebral Regenerative Compound</ntg.title.nerve_generators>
<ntg.description.nerve_generators>Medical Skill Check: 50.
\nA compound used to regenerate dead brain tissue and restore brain function. It can be used to remove all lobotomy-related afflictions; good and bad.
\nThis skill check can never be failed.
</ntg.description.nerve_generators>
<ntg.applicationsuccess.nerve_generators>
    Removes all lobotomy-related afflictions
</ntg.applicationsuccess.nerve_generators>
<ntg.seealso.nerve_generators>
    [cerebral_regeneration_procedure] Cerebral Regeneration Surgery 
</ntg.seealso.nerve_generators>

<!-- Transorbital Lobotomy -->
<ntg.title.transorbital_lobotomy>Transorbital Lobotomy</ntg.title.transorbital_lobotomy>
<ntg.description.transorbital_lobotomy>A method of lobotomizing that relies on an Orbitoclast and a Surgical Hammer to cause (hopefully positive) brain damage.
\nSince this procedure is cheap and relatively 'simple', the chance to recieve negative effects is higher compared to an Ethanol lobotomy.
\nA patient has a 15% chance to recieve a positive effect from this surgery.
</ntg.description.transorbital_lobotomy>
<ntg.steps.transorbital_lobotomy>
    [orbitoclast] 1. Apply the Orbitoclast to the Head |
    [surgical_hammer] 2. Apply the Surgical Hammer to the Head |
    [analgesia] 3. Give patient Painkillers (optional)
</ntg.steps.transorbital_lobotomy>
<ntg.seealso.transorbital_lobotomy>
    [ethanol_lobotomy] Ethanol Lobotomy |
    [cerebral_regeneration_procedure] Cure lobotomies with Cerebral Regeneration Surgery |
    [lobotomy_effects] List of possible Lobotomy effects (SPOILER WARNING)
</ntg.seealso.transorbital_lobotomy>

<!-- Ethanol Lobotomy -->
<ntg.title.ethanol_lobotomy>Ethanol Lobotomy</ntg.title.ethanol_lobotomy>
<ntg.description.ethanol_lobotomy>A method of lobotomizing that uses Ethanol to cause (hopefully positive) brain damage. 
\nThis procedure is harder and more expensive than the other method, and thus has a higher chance to give positive effects.
\nA patient has a 20% chance to recieve a positive effect from this surgery.
</ntg.description.ethanol_lobotomy>
<ntg.steps.ethanol_lobotomy>
    [analgesia] 1a. Analgesia | 
    [anesthesia] 1b. Anesthesia |
    [multipurpose_scalpel] 2a. Apply a Multipurpose Scalpel in the Surgical Incision mode to the Head |
    [scalpel] 2b. Apply a Scalpel to the Head | 
    [hemostat] 3. Apply a Hemostat | 
    [skin_retractors] 4. Apply Skin Retractors | 
    [surgical_drill] 5. Apply a Surgical Drill |
    6. Apply Ethanol |
    [sutures] 7. Apply a Suture |
    8. Give patient Painkillers (optional)
</ntg.steps.ethanol_lobotomy>
<ntg.seealso.ethanol_lobotomy>
    [transorbital_lobotomy] Transorbital Lobotomy |
    [cerebral_regeneration_procedure] Cure lobotomies with Cerebral Regeneration Surgery |
    [lobotomy_effects] List of possible Lobotomy effects (SPOILER WARNING)
</ntg.seealso.ethanol_lobotomy>

<!-- Cerebral Regeneration Surgery -->
<ntg.title.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>Cerebral Regeneration Surgery</ntg.title.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>
<ntg.description.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>A surgery to reverse the effects of a lobotomy on living patients.
\n‖color:245,71,71,255‖Cerebral Regenerative Compound should not be applied to a normal, healthy brain under any circumstance.‖end‖</ntg.description.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>
<ntg.steps.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>
    [analgesia] 1a. Analgesia | 
    [anesthesia] 1b. Anesthesia |
    [multipurpose_scalpel] 2a. Apply a Multipurpose Scalpel in the Surgical Incision mode to the Head |
    [scalpel] 2b. Apply a Scalpel to the Head | 
    [hemostat] 3. Apply a Hemostat | 
    [skin_retractors] 4. Apply Skin Retractors | 
    [surgical_drill] 5. Apply a Surgical Drill |
    [nerve_generators] 6. Administer Cerebral Regenerative Compound (CRC) |
    [sutures] 7. Apply a Suture |
</ntg.steps.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>
<ntg.seealso.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>
    [transorbital_lobotomy] Transorbital Lobotomy |
    [ethanol_lobotomy] Ethanol Lobotomy 
</ntg.seealso.cerebral_regeneration_procedure>

<!-- Lobotomy Effects -->
<ntg.title.lobotomy_effects>Possible Lobotomy Effects</ntg.title.lobotomy_effects>
<ntg.description.lobotomy_effects>This page will contain all of the possible negative and positive effects.
There are 8 positive effects and 26 negative effects.
\nContents of this page were written by the excellent Wormy.
\nDo not read further if you do not want to be spoiled.
</ntg.description.lobotomy_effects>
<ntg.lobopositiveeffects.lobotomy_effects>
    Congenital Analgesia: Patient exhibits immunity to Intense Pain. |
    Desensitized: Patient is immune to Traumatic Shock. |
    Genius: Patient's skills are effectively doubled (via bonus). |
    Heightened Alcohol Tolerance: Patient gains incredibly high resistance towards acquiring the “drunk” affliction, but can still gain buffs such as psychosis resistance from drinking alcohol. |
    Hyperkinetic Movement Disorder: Patient gains increased movement speed. |
    Increased Cerebral Regeneration: Patient rapidly recovers from Neurotrauma. |
    Psychological Potence: Patient becomes immune to Psychosis. |
    Stun Resistance: Patient becomes incredibly resistant to the “stunned” status effect, but can still be knocked down by impact and attacks.
</ntg.lobopositiveeffects.lobotomy_effects>
<ntg.lobonegativeeffects.lobotomy_effects>
    Abnormal Brain-Lung Crosstalk: Patient will go into Respiratory Arrest every couple of seconds. |
    Abnormal Gait: Patient's movement speed is reduced, and limbs are stiffened - similar to large amounts of blunt-force trauma. |
    Auditory Hallucinations: Patient periodically hears whispers and voices in their head. |
    Severe Auditory Hallucinations: Patient periodically hears jarringly loud human screams from nearby. |
    Deafness: All local sound effects are severely muffled to the patient. |
    Fibromyalgia: Patient experiences sporadic Intense Pain throughout every limb. |
    Gas Incontinence: Patient will produce audible fart sound effects at regular intervals. |
    Heightened Opioid Resistance: Patient develops high resistance to and rapid recovery from Analgesia. Potentially prevents Opioid Withdrawal/Addiction afflictions. |
    Hyperactivity: Locks the patient into sprinting by removing the ability to walk. Can still stop in place and walk backwards. |
    Hypoactivity: Patient loses the ability to sprint. |
    Intellectual Disability: Patient suffers a negative “bonus” to their skills. |
    Mania: Patient's walk-cycle is replaced with the “Vigorous Walk”. |
    Mutism: Patient is unable to give commands via command interface. Text chat and voice chat still (maybe?) work. |
    Narcolepsy: Patient will fall Unconscious at random intervals |
    Protensive Psychotic Disorder: Patient develops permanent Psychosis |
    Psychopathy: Patient “swaps teams” and becomes marked as a hostile. |
    Reduced Motor Skills: Reduces patient's walking speed, and changes animations to match being concussed/drunk. Running speed is unaffected, but animation is also changed. |
    Severed Motor Connections: Patient is permanently stunned. |
    Somatic Nerve Reversion: Patient's movement controls are inverted |
    Tinnitus: Patient will continually hear a high-pitched ringing sound. |
    Tourette's Syndrome: Patients will occasionally scream. |
    Tunnel Vision: Removes much of the patient's field of view (akin to being inside of a diving suit) and activates a line-of-sight version of vision. |
    Vertigo: Patient has permanent nausea. |
    Virtual Earthquake Syndrome: The environment around the patient will appear to shake (similar to phantom-impacts caused by Psychosis). |
    Vision Loss: Patient's vision is blurred. |
    William's Syndrome: Patient's walk cycle changes to the “Jolly Walk”. |
</ntg.lobonegativeeffects.lobotomy_effects>
<ntg.seealso.lobotomy_effects>
    [transorbital_lobotomy] Transorbital Lobotomy |
    [ethanol_lobotomy] Ethanol Lobotomy |
    [cerebral_regeneration_procedure] Cerebral Regeneration Surgery
</ntg.seealso.lobotomy_effects>

</Infotexts>